<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab on OS Labs</title>
    <link>/tags/lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab on OS Labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 03:43:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab 4: Shell and Bootloader Phase 2</title>
      <link>/post/lab4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lab4/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started Fetch the update for lab 4 from our git repository to your development machine.&#xA;git fetch skeleton git merge skeleton/lab4 You may need to resolve conflicts before continuing. For example, if you see a message that looks like:&#xA;Auto-merging kern/src/main.rs CONFLICT (content): Merge conflict in kern/src/main.rs Automatic merge failed; fix conflicts and then commit the result. You will need to manually modify the relevent files to resolve the conflict.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3: Shell and Bootloader Phase 1</title>
      <link>/post/lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lab3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this assignment, you will write useful utilities, libraries, and a simple shell for Raspberry Pi. This is just a single phase of this exercise and we&amp;rsquo;ll be going over the rest of them in the incoming weeks.&#xA;Please insure you&amp;rsquo;ve setup the environment as described on Tools page .&#xA;This is the directory structure of our repository. The directories you will be working on this lab section are marked with *.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/post/env_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/env_setup/</guid>
      <description>Setting up the environment Before starting to this series of lab assignments, please make sure that you have followed the environment setup described below.&#xA;Our labs are designed based on Ubuntu 20.04 LTS. This is done using docker so that everyone has similar setups.&#xA;We recommend you to stick to this ubuntu version unless you might face some configuration issues.&#xA;You will also be using use QEMU, an x86 emulator for easier executing and debugging process instead of using real raspberry pi board.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
